Yeah, welcome to another video and in this video we will going to see the
might attack the kx filtration, okay. So most of the courses they won't cover
about the x filtration or later commands how the attacker will do the
exfiltrations, okay. So in this video we will see how to exfiltrate a data from
how to exfiltrate a data from a term machine to the cloud platform, okay. So what's an
exfiltration? So let's think about what is an exfiltration. So exfiltration is
like you are just uploading an important and confidential data to the cloud,
okay. So if you take an organization the organization absolutely have a
confidential data that will not be shared to anyone, right. So threat
tactor once they will fulfill all the mitotatics of
previous legislation and credential access and before the ransomware deployment
they will go for exfiltration, okay. So if they exfiltrate all the data from the
target machine, if the target, if the target organization will not pay the
ransomware ransomware money they will upload, they will publish that
confidential files and contents in a dark web, okay. In a dark web or they will
publish in an online, okay. So that will be a serious threat, okay. So the
organization have most confidential data that will be used for our future but
the threat attacker will steal that kind of data and they will simply
upload that data into the internet and public forum, okay. So that will be one of
the serious issue, okay. So if you tracking the exfiltration later activities,
if you are investigating exfiltration later activities it's not a simple thing,
okay. So we will see how to investigate the exfiltration things in a
bluetooth section, investigation section, there is a separate section that
was available. So in this video we will see how to exfiltrate the data from the
target machine to cloud, okay. So I have already created a mega account, so in
this video we are going to upload our data into the mega, okay. Mega is one of
a cloud platform, so you will get a lot of data from mega, okay. So give me a
you may sometime my machine was still stuck, okay. So let I will, I think I need to
restart my machine, I will restart my machine and I will be back, okay. Let's power
off and let's start a machine, okay. I did not expect that this machine was
hanged. So not a problem, we will discuss the thing, okay. For exfiltrating the
data, now we are professional in red team, right. Now we are professional in
red team because the class are multiple things, okay. We did initial access,
differentiation, privilege escalation, credential access, etc, etc, right. So we did
lot of things and now we are professional in relative related activities,
okay. To uploading a data into the mega, so here we are using, I already told in
our log bin, so there is a R code.exe that can be abused by other
attackers to exfiltrated a data, right. So for that you need to download our
clone.exe from the website, okay. So if you go to the Google and if you give the R clone,
R clone.exe and you can click on the download button, you can download a Intel AMD 64
or 32 bit, okay. So whatever you want, okay. I already downloaded the R clone.exe
into my downloads and here you can find the R clone folder, okay. So what I did,
I just copied this application to the system 32, okay. I just copied this
application and said the system 32 folder, so here you can find the R clone,
R clone.exe, okay. So we are using the R clone.exe to exfiltrate the data
from the target machine to the cloud, okay. So this is the first video, this one
of the method that was frequently used by the threat actor to exfiltrate the
data, okay. And in the right hand side, if I go to my Kali machine, so let's open
the mega, okay. Let it be load, do some time.
I just, let's give me a few seconds more, yep. So we are using this mega to
upload the data to our data like platform, okay. So you can see there is a
directory which I have created called the exfil, okay. So if you want to create a
directory in mega, if you want to sign in into a mega, you can create your
account in mega and once you create your own account, your front page will
be looked like this, okay. So if you want to create any folder, you can, you can
give that. So if I give the ransom, so it will be, it will be created, okay. The
folder will be automatically created, okay. So that's all about the mega thing
and we will, we have successfully created our account and all, I can see there's
a two folder which I have created on this exfil and on this ransom. And I hope
you will also create the mega, there was a very simple one, it's like a Google
Drive, okay. So if you go to the target machine, so now we are
professionals, right. If I explain in the target machine, so it will easily
understand what happened, how to, how to do exfiltration, okay. So you need to
configure the, configure the R clone, okay. So once you install the R clone in
target machine, okay, in a target machine, so you can do it, do it like you can
transfer the R clone using the 30 alert bits admin and you can execute in the,
execute the R clone in the target machine and you can, you need to configure,
okay. You need to configure something, I have created the name of AJAY and I, I
gave the, if you want to give your R clone config, okay, in a command first, okay. So
then it will last for what editing you need. So if you need to create a new
remote or a rename or copy anything, so I just created a one, editing the
existing thing and there's some configuration source available, okay. So if you
see in the 29th storage, you can find the mega here. So I gave 29 and I gave
the user name to my email and password us take my mega password, okay. So the
password will be my mega password and if I give the, sorry, R clone, let me
recover the command, yeah, list l i s t or mo t s, okay. So, okay, cool R clone is
not a, organized command, we will do one thing, so we will execute like this, R
clone dot exes, still it will also be not organized, yeah, now it came R clone dot exes a
list remotes, okay. So it was asking, okay, so R clone dot exes list remotes, so this
right command, so here you can find the, I have created the mega and if I, you
are clone l s f and the, the name mega, so it will recover all the folders which
we have created. So you can see here X phil and ransom which we have created recently
the ransom we have created and in this video, I will, I will take on file as a target,
okay, this is t, this is the file, we are going to upload, okay, l s s dot DMP, so here
you can find the similar command, okay. So the command will be R clone dot exes and we are
going to copy the l s s dump and mega is my name of the configurations, I did some configuration
right. So X will use a folder, you need, you need to give the folder which folder we need
to upload, okay, and this argument, this was an optional because if you are uploading multiple
files in a one shot, you need to create a streams, okay, because the internet speeds it
will vary of, you know, organization, so your R clone activity will not upload the data sometimes,
so we are giving some of the, some of the additional flags to resolve that issue, okay.
Okay, sometime the organization will set the rules like this is that if it exceeds more,
more data, your firewall block, okay, so it will bypass this kind of restriction, okay.
So let's copy this command, and let's check the mega, okay, so there is no files instead
of the folder, let's execute this command, okay, so hope you all can see the commands
which I have did, I just copy paste or the l s dot dump, the target folder, and mega
X fill, okay, so if I do enter, so my data was uploading, okay, let's go move to the configuration
later thing, okay, yeah, these are all the configuration you can see which I did before,
there was a easy configuration, not a tough one, so you can also do it if you want, and
if I go to the target folder, the mega app, you can see the l s dot dump here, it was
51 MB, right, so this is how the threat actors will, threat actors will exfiltrate the
data from the target machines using the orthorn.exe, okay, so another one thing, we all know
orthorn.exe was used for an exfiltration, right, so sometime what threat actor will do,
the threat actor will rename the orthorn to some other executeable, okay, so if you do the
for an example, or clone, okay, so what is the threat actor will do, they will rename
the r clone to the run the l l r s v c host or any other executeable, okay, they will rename
that r clone.exe into any name, partial.exe or any other, any other Google.exe, anything,
okay, they will rename it like anything and they will use that, they will use the, the
original binary was an r clone, okay, the original binary was an r clone, if you check the
name of the executeable, the executeable will be f v c host or s a host or conv host, okay,
so this is one of the mechanism that was followed by the threat actor, okay, so as a threat
analyst, if you are, if there is an exfiltration that was happening, you will directly see
the r clone activity, right, so what they will do, they will rename the r clone into
other executable and they will do the exfiltration, okay, like this, okay, this is what
threat actors will do and this is how the threat actor will exfiltrate the data from the
target machines, okay, so you need to aware about this activity, if there is a ransomware
deployment, if the threat actor goal is ransomware deployment, they will absolutely do this
step, okay, they will absolutely follow the exfiltration step to upload the data to the cloud
machine, okay, yep, that's all about the video, we will meet you in the next video, thank
you for watching, okay, next video we will see some third party application that was
used for an exfiltration, okay, so yeah, hope you understand this video, we will meet
do in the next video. Thank you. Thank you for watching.